https://www.pri.org/privacy

Skip to content
close
The World needs you. We need 471 more donors to reach our goal!
Donate $100 or pledge $8.33/month to receive an invite to a virtual party with Marco Werman and The World team!Our coverage never has been, and never will be, behind a paywall.Donate today to support our freely available journalism.
Yes, donate now!
No thank you
Close
Search
About UsContactDonate Now
Listen navigate down
The World's PodcastThe Number in the News for smartspeakersGlobal HitMusic Heard on AirStations Listing
Newsletters navigate down
Top of The World daily newsletterCritical State
Categories navigate down
Conflict & JusticeCulture & SocietyDevelopment & EducationHealth & MedicineImmigrationMoneyPoliticsScience & EnvironmentTechnologyWomen & Gender
PRI.org privacy policy
PRI.org is owned and operated by Public Radio International (referred to herein as “Public Radio International,” “PRI,” “we,” and “us”).  PRI respects your individual privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, and share information we obtain from users in connection with any mobile services, websites including without limitation any website displaying or linking to this Privacy Policy, live stream, RSS feeds, APIs and any software provided on or in connection with the PRI service (collectively the “Service”). By using the Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy is subject to the PRI.org Complete Terms of Service and User Agreement terms, including without limitation its warranty disclaimer, limitation of liability, and choice of law and venue provisions.
What information do we collect?
Personal Information:
We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form.
When registering on our site or making a donation, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, email address, mailing address, social media profiles, phone number, credit card information or other information. You may also visit our site anonymously.
Non-Personal Information:
You may also visit our site anonymously.  We, and vendors operating on our behalf, may collect logs of visits and that data may be used by us for analytical purposes to understand general traffic patterns and also for customer support, trouble shooting, improving or enhancing the Services, and security monitoring purposes.  Information collected may include, for example, your IP address, browser type, domain names, access types, and referring web site addresses.
Information that you provide to us as of user-submitted content will typically become public once submitted.
What do we use your information for?
In addition to the purposes otherwise listed in this Privacy Policy, any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:
• To personalize your experience
Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
• To improve our website
We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
• To improve customer service
Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
• To process transactions
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.
• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
• To send periodic emails
The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to your inquiries and/or ask other requests or questions.
Communications between PRI and users
If you indicate on your registration form that you want to receive such information, we, our owners and assigns, will allow certain third party vendors to provide you with information about products and services using the information you provided. PRI reserves the right to send electronic mail to you for the purpose of informing you of changes or additions to the Service.
PRI may contact you via e-mail regarding your participation in user surveys, asking for feedback on the current Service or prospective products and services. This information will be used to improve the Services and better understand our users, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.
Donations
PRI does not sell, trade, rent or share its contributor information to third parties. PRI secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. PRI secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol, an industry standard secure technology.
How do we protect your information?
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit or access your personal information.
We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Database to be only accessed by those authorized with special access rights to our systems, and who are required to keep the information confidential.
After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.
Do we use cookies?
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow this.) Cookies enable a site or service provider system to recognize your browser and capture and retain certain information.
We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are only permitted to use the information collected on our behalf to help us conduct and improve our business.
We may use cookies to place ads on our site based on your visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Other third parties may also place cookies or other tracking devices on your computer or mobile device for the purpose of tracking your online behaviors across non-PRI affiliated websites and you may be delivered targeted advertisements on PRI’s Services related to such tracked online behavior.  PRI does not control the actions of these third parties and you are encouraged to read the privacy policies for the third party websites you visit.
Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect our or others' rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. You may opt out of advertising tracking via the Digital Advertising Alliance's opt-out page.
Third party links
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Google Analytics features
We use Google Analytics to track demographic and interest data of our online users, in aggregate. The information is not tracked on an individual level, but it is viewed in aggregate to give us an idea of who our audience is and to inform our decisions on what sort of content they might be interested in. We may also share aggregate data with funders and editorial partners. If you wish to opt our of this tracking, you may do so via Google's Ads Settings control panel, or it compansion Ad Settings for mobile apps.
California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
Because we value your privacy, we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.
As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at any time by logging into their control panel and going to the 'Edit Profile' page.
Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), so we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.  IF YOU ARE NOT 13 YEARS OF AGE, DO NOT USE THIS WEBSITE WITHOUT APPROVAL FROM YOUR PARENTS OR GUARDIAN.  If you are the parent or guardian of a person under 18 and believe that your child has provided Personal Information to us, please contact us using the contact information listed below.
Online Privacy Policy Only
This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and other digital services and not to information collected offline.
Do Not Track
We do not at this time honor your do not track requests by not tracking you according to the do not track selections you have made using your web browser settings.  As our web site evolves, we may add do not track functionality.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. Check back often to review such changes.
Contacting Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.
PRI.org401 2nd Ave North, Suite 500Minneapolis, MN 55401USAcontact@pri.org
Last Modified: February 12, 2016
© 2018 Public Radio International, All Rights Reserved
Share
logo-footer
Created with Sketch.
The World is a public radio program that crosses borders and time zones to bring home the stories that matter.
Produced by
GBH_logo_purple_rgb
Created with Sketch.
Major funding provided by
close
We use cookies to understand how you use our site and to improve your experience. To learn more, review our Cookie Policy. By continuing to use our site, you accept our use of cookies and Privacy Policy.
Ok, I understand.
Close
close
Donate $100 or pledge $8.33/month to receive an invite to a virtual party with Marco Werman and The World team! We need just 471 more donors to make it! When you support The World with a donation, you ensure our incredible newsroom staff can continue the critical work that brings you stories from around the globe. Donate today to help keep our coverage free and open to all. Thank you for your support!
DONATE TODAY >
No thanks
